I ended up not doing anything.
I wonder if they'll be mad.
Though in contrast,
you worked too hard.
Poor thing.
Shall I put you out of your misery?
Good work.
You're just a human. Don't act on your own.
Or I'll kill you.
Come on, I'm just being nice.
But I guess a curse wouldn't
understand such subtleties.
So, got the goods?
Without a hitch.
All six of the special-grade
"Sukuna's Finger" cursed objects
that Jujutsu High possessed...
and the other special-grade cursed object,
"Cursed Wombs: Death Paintings,"
One through Three.
Most of the temples at Jujutsu High
are actually just a facade.
Tengen's barrier keeps their
position changing every day.
Among those, only one
of over a thousand doors
leads to the storeroom
that holds cursed objects
as dangerous as the fingers.
Only Tengen knows which door leads
to the storehouse each day,
so I doubt anyone will interfere.
Who's Tengen?
A jujutsu sorcerer with
an immortality technique.
Immortality?!
Who's stronger, him or Gojo Satoru?!
He has immortality, but not eternal youth.
You can think of him as just a tree.
Tengen basically doesn't
interfere with the world,
aside from maintaining barriers.
You really don't have to worry about him.
Remember the finger we let
Jujutsu High retrieve previously?
I placed a charm comprised of Mahito's
cursed energy on it before they collected it.
It's under a single-layer seal,
so they won't remove it.
He'll be able to find it easily.
Any gatekeepers?
There are two of Tengen's attendants
between the door and the storeroom,
but they're chumps.
More importantly, before the veil goes down,
I'd like you to thin out the sorcerers standing
by at Jujutsu High as quietly as possible.
We want to reduce the burden on Hanami.
Why aren't we sealing
Gojo Satoru within the veil?
Because we don't want him to direct his
attention toward Mahito's main mission.
And we need him to exercise
a degree of his full power,
or it won't be a proper test of the veil.
Trapping the students inside
will be more effective.
Is it okay to kill all but Sukuna's vessel?
That's fine, but I wouldn't recommend it.
Sukuna's actions
aren't quite what I had imagined.
This is just my guess,
but I believe one of the students
acts as a land mine for Sukuna.
If we step on that,
then in the worst case, all of our
current plans will be ruined.
We should just kidnap Itadori ahead of time.
He's a pawn we'll be using anyway.
No, Itadori...
or rather, Sukuna himself, is also a bomb.
Both for us and for Jujutsu High.
We shouldn't agitate it until
the moment we want more chaos:
October 31st, in Shibuya.
We should keep everything we can use
to seal Gojo Satoru in reserve until then.
We'll have a few curse
users accompany us, too,
but Kumiya Juzo...
He's disposable.
He's not the kind of person who can
follow a plan all the way through.
He'll get in our way later.
We'll have a different human monitoring
our commissioned test run of the veil,
so get along with them.
Hear that? Get along, Jogo!
Hmph!
I'm not going, anyway.
Come on, wake up, Hanami.
Let's go home.
Mahito.
Trying to pump the brakes on
my hostility is incredibly stressful.
You're sounding more
like a curse, too, Hanami.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Tokyo
Jujutsu
High
School
Episode 21: Jujutsu Koshien
Next up are the casualties.
Three second-grade sorcerers,
one semi-first-grade sorcerer,
five assistant supervisors,
and two cursed storehouse guards.
They're all sorcerers who were
standing by at Jujutsu High
and working separately from
Gojo-san and Principal Yaga.
We're waiting on the report from Ieiri-san,
but we're nearly certain it was
the work of the cursed spirit
that Nanami-san encountered before.
Tsk.
Do you think we should share this information
with the students and the other sorcerers?
No.
It's probably better to keep
this among the higher-ups.
We don't want to give curse users certainty
that special-grade objects were stolen.
Has the curse user we
captured spilled anything?
It's not hard to get him to talk,
but most of what he says
is irrelevant nonsense.
However, he claims that he
only participated in the attack
because he was ordered to as part of a deal.
I wanted to make a coat rack.
That monk promised me that.
I don't know their name.
I couldn't tell if they were a man or woman.
Just a brat with white hair in a bob cut.
An androgynous monk kid with a bob cut?
That ring any bells?
Nope.
We sure he's not spouting bullshit?
Is there any sorcerer skilled
at getting confessions?
How did a cursed spirit and outsiders
get through Tengen-sama's
barriers in the first place?
That was probably the work of the
special-grade cursed spirit the students fought.
That one has a unique presence.
Even though it's a cursed spirit,
it's incredibly close to a natural spirit.
According to Aoi, it was
able to hide among plants.
And Tengen-sama's barrier
doesn't function against plants.
Tengen-sama's barrier puts all its
power into hiding, not protecting.
So once you get in, it's kind of weak.
Are they worried about Sukuna's
Fingers enhancing Yuji's potential?
Or are they trying to enhance themselves?
Something isn't sitting right.
For now, let's be glad our students are safe.
But it goes without saying that the
exchange event is now canceled.
Hold on.
That's not for us to decide, is it?
When did you start getting
along with that gorilla?
Well, we got along, but like...
I remember what happened,
but I wasn't exactly myself then...
What, were you drunk?
You believe I could've been
drinking liquor in that situation?
I'm shocked.
But I'm glad you weren't
seriously hurt, Fushiguro.
You're able to eat pizza now, too.
Come on, bring me
something easier to digest.
No complaining.
Apparently, I got off easier because
my cursed energy was all dried up.
Ieiri-san was still able to fix me up
as soon as the roots were removed.
Huh, so that's a thing that can happen?
You fought against them, didn't you?
Itadori.
You've grown stronger.
Back then, we both said our
convictions were proper ones.
I still think that's true.
Or, put another way, we're both wrong.
Huh?
Some questions don't have answers, you know.
You're thinking too hard.
You'll go bald.
That's right. There is no answer.
It's just whether or not you can accept it.
But there's no accepting anything
if you can't have it your way.
Weak sorcerers can't do that.
So I'm going to become strong, too.
I'll surpass you in no time.
You never change.
Don't just move the conversation
forward without me.
That's my brother's friends for you!
Where are you going, Brother?!
I'm grateful to you, but give me a break!
I wasn't thinking straight then!
What're you saying?!
We've been so close since
middle school, Brother!
I didn't go to your middle school!
Curse
Hello! Useless Miwa here!
Even though I call myself useless,
I don't think I'm actually that bad.
But while everyone was risking their lives
fighting during the special-grade
cursed spirit's attack,
I was fast asleep,
and now I feel ashamed.
Also, who broke my sword?
Was it Mai's older sister?
Between all that, we thought
the exchange event was canceled,
but after taking a day off,
we're now...
Play ball!
...playing baseball.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
— One Day Prior —
So anyway,
a lot happened and some people died,
but how about it? Want to
continue the exchange event?
I don't know what to say about it...
Obviously...
We're continuing it, of course.
T-Todo!
Your reasons?
First, only those with a connection to
the dead have a right to mourn them.
It's not our place to butt in there.
And second, if people have died,
that's all the more reason
we need to become stronger.
Acquired strength comes from
the accumulation of results.
Tasting defeat and savoring victory
is what leads us to grow.
The most important part is
for those results to exist.
Todo-senpai's surprisingly reliable.
Reliably crazy.
Third, when a student feels like they
weren't able to bring out their best,
it hangs over them until they die.
How old are you?
I'm fine with that.
We'll win anyway.
It sounds stupid, but he has a point.
Why don't you rest, Kamo-kun?
No objections here.
Salmon.
Will we draw lots for the
individual battle pair-ups?
Huh?
There are no individual battles this year.
The exchange event has the principals
of the Tokyo and Kyoto schools
each propose a form of competition to be held
for an entire day over the course of two days.
But that's just how it is on paper.
Every year, the first day is team battles,
and the second day is individual battles.
Salmon.
I hate routines, you know.
Every year, we put the
competition methods in this box
and open it on the day of.
*Principal Gakuganji's previous visit was to discuss
what items might be needed on the day of the event.
Principal Gakuganji's
previous visit was to discuss
what items might be needed
on the day of the event.
Baseball
Baseball?!
You're here, too?!
What's going on here, Yaga?
No, I know I put individual battles in—
Get back here, Satoru!
Miwa Kasumi
Second Base
The mango she was letting ripen in the refrigerator is gone.
Fly ball!
Nishimiya, don't run yet!
Out!
Huh? Why?
If you don't know the rules, then say so!
I know them! When the ball's hit, I run!
Nishimiya Momo
Outfielder
Baseball experience: 2L.
A sacrifice fly?!
What's that, some new form of torture?!
You're just plain stupid!
Kamo Noritoshi
Third batter
Practicing cursive. I can write my own name now.
I heard you fended off a special-grade.
Itadori Yuji
Catcher
First impression of iekei ramen: "I poop a lot the next day."
Huh?
Oh, yeah...
thanks to Todo and Gojo-sensei.
Don't you need a helmet?
Itadori, why are you a jujutsu sorcerer?
At first, it just kinda happened.
But I'm a lonely guy.
I want to save lots of people
and have lots of them
watching over me when I die.
If you're not there, Mother,
I won't become a jujutsu sorcerer!
You have talent, Noritoshi.
You can save lots of people.
The more people you save,
the more you'll be recognized.
Then, in turn, all kinds
of people will help you.
You'll only be alone for now.
One day, once you've
become a great sorcerer,
come get me.
I see.
That's
a good
reason.
Strike!
Batter out!
Change up!
Kamo! You won't get a hit if you don't swing!
Kyoto
Tokyo
They call me the Mah-kun of Tohoku.
Kugisaki Nobara
Third Base
Awaiting approval for a credit card. Too hard for a high schooler, maybe?
No, Mah-kun is the Mah-kun of Tohoku.
Mah-kun's a pitcher, you know!
Bonito flakes.
Huh?
Mechamaru
Hold on!
Kugisaki's snapped!
It's a free-for-all!
That's obviously a pitching machine!
What are you talking about?
It's a spare. A spare Mechamaru.
Mechamaru
We don't have a choice, since your
Panda broke him the other day.
Pitching machine?
Zen'in Mai
First Base
Hated mangoes, but got over it recently.
I don't understand.
You know a lot about machines.
Are you an otaku?
It's just one thing after another with you!
And yet somehow you're
still a Jujutsu High student!
Fine, I'll do this!
Oh, she got on base.
She's desperate.
Fushiguro Megumi
Outfielder
Prefers breast meat in chicken nanban and thigh meat in oyakodon.
Out.
Panda
First Base
Wants to punch a zebra someday.
Zen'in Maki
Pitcher
The one thing she can't tolerate is protein powder.
Tsk.
Mechamaru
Okay, that's three.
That's cheating!
Bonito flakes!
Kugisaki, go back.
Due to lack of players, one outfielder is permitted to use cursed techniques.
Kyoto
Tokyo
Catcher, huh?
Todo Aoi
Catcher
Won the middle school nationals with Itadori. Itadori denies this.
Catching, throwing, leading, fielding, etc.
One could call it a fitting
position for my brother.
But what I desire is a face-off
with Pitcher Itadori.
Todo...
You could have been their pitcher.
He can't.
Mechamaru can't do anything
but pitch right now.
Promise me, Brother.
If I hit a home run at bat this time,
next time you'll pi—
Intentional
T-Todo!
Hang in there!
Nice pitch!
Maki-san, nice pitch!
Todo,
everyone
really hates you!
Do you still hate Itadori?
It's not a matter of liking or hating him.
Itadori isn't allowed to
exist under jujutsu laws.
He's only alive due to Gojo's selfishness.
We must not bend the rules
of the group for the individual.
Moreover, many others may
die because Itadori lives.
But there are lives that
were saved thanks to him, too.
Case in point, he worked together
with Todo to fend off the special-grade.
This doesn't apply to just our students,
but they're going to stack up
many regrets as time goes on.
"I wish I had done that."
"I wish they'd done this."
"I should have said that."
"I wish someone had told me this."
To be honest with you, I don't know
what the right decision is with Itadori.
But for now, let's just watch over him.
Oh, he made it!
Inumaki-senpai's a fast runner.
Salted roe.
Inumaki Toge
Second Base
Prefers bread for breakfast. Likes it with ham, cheese, and a bit of tabasco.
Mai! Miwa!
Watch for base-stealing!
We can save our regrets
for after that.
He nailed it.
Yeah!
Sister School Exchange Event
Second Day's Baseball Competition
Tokyo
Kyoto
30th Annual Exchange Event
Winner: Tokyo
Yaga, do something about Gojo first.
Juju Stroll
Salmon.
Q: Rice or bread?
Rice?
Q: Are you a rice person or a bread person?
No, I like bread, too...
Wait, is it served with roe?
Q: Are you a rice person or a bread person?
Rice.
Rice, I think?
Q: Are you a rice person or a bread person?
What? I definitely prefer bread.
Salted rice ball.
Obviously bread, because I'm a panda!
Q: Are you a rice person or a bread person?
You want me to kill you?!
This one's...
kind of forced...
They're out of ideas.
We're going home.
Episode 22:
The Origin of Blind Obedience